<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
    <resources>
        <string-array name = "answers11">
            <item>The main cause of cervical cancer is Human Papillomavirus (HPV). This sexually transmitted infection, if left untreated, may result in cervical cancer after many years of infection. However, this is not always the case. Often times, the body is able to get rid of the infection on its own. In fact, most women with HPV do not end up getting cervical cancer.</item>
            <item>Having an HPV infection does not mean that you have cervical cancer. However, if the infection remains untreated, you will be at higher risk of developing cervical cancer.</item>
            <item>After many years in the female body, HPV causes the normal cells on the surface of the cervix to change into pre-cancerous cells. If the body is not able to get rid of these cells or if they are not removed/destroyed by treatment, they can develop into cervical cancer. </item>
            <item>No. Although HPV is a sexually-transmitted infection, cervical cancer is not directly caused by sex. Almost all sexually active women will never develop cervical precancer or cancer. Rather, a woman would have to be infected with HPV and the virus would have to remain in her system for a long period of time.</item>
            <item>No. Contraceptives do not cause cervical cancer or HPV infection. Some research shows extended use of oral contraceptives (5+ years) may increase risk, but that is likely related to lower condom use (which reduces the risk of HPV acquisition). In fact, IUD use may decrease risk. ?</item>
            <item>No. cervical cancer is caused by long-term infection with HPV. A woman cannot get cervical cancer from sex while on her period.</item>
            <item>No. The act of touching the cervix does not cause cervical cancer. While there may be risk of other types of infections if the provider is not operating in a sterile environment or with sterile instruments, there is no chance of contracting HPV since it is only spread through sexual contact of infected bodily fluids or skin-to-skin gentile contact.</item>
            <item>No. HPV is spread through sexual contact with an infected individual.</item>
            <item>The early signs of cervical cancer can be detected by pap test (screening). These signs are usually precancerous lesions on the surface of the cervix, and can only be seen through a microscope. A woman usually does not show signs of cervical cancer in its earlier stages. As it advances, woman may notice unusual bleeding or discharge, such as after sex. Also, pain during sex is possible, pelvic pain, weight loss, fatigue, or leg swelling/pain that is not equal on both sides.</item>
            <item>A woman may not show signs of cervical cancer in its earlier stages. As it advances, woman may notice unusual bleeding or discharge, such as after sex. Also, pain during sex is possible, as well as pelvic pain, weight loss, fatigue, or a single swollen leg.</item>
            <item>The types of HPV that cause cervical cancer do not usually cause any symptoms. Most people do not know they have it. Some HPV types cause warts, but these types do not cause cervical cancer.</item>
            <item>Being HPV positive is not a death sentence. HPV is the most common sexually transmitted infection. Many people’s bodies are able to clear the infection within a relatively short time period. However, if the infection persists and is left untreated, it can cause problems. Getting an HPV diagnosis means that you have the opportunity for treatment, which can reduce your risk for cancer and for re-infection.</item>
            <item>Having cervical cancer is not automatically a death sentence. cervical cancer is usually treatable, especially if detected early. These tests are screening for HPV, however, and do not mean that you would have cervical cancer.</item>
            <item>As the cancer becomes more advanced (spreads beyond cervical tissue), it is harder to treat. If the cancer advances too far, it can lead to complications, such as bleeding, pain and difficulty urinating. If left too long or untreated, women can die from cervical cancer.</item>
            <item>HPV infection does not cause miscarriage.  Screening using self-collection does not cause miscarriage or impact the pregnancy, however treatment should be delayed until after pregnancy. cervical cancer itself does not cause miscarriage, but sometimes treatment for cervical cancer may disrupt pregnancy.</item>
            <item>HPV infection does not cause infertility.  Screening using self-collection and treatment with cryotherapy do not cause infertility. cervical cancer itself does not cause infertility, but sometimes treatment for cervical cancer may prevent women from getting pregnant in the future.</item>
            <item>There is some chance that treatment can affect a woman’s fertility, because treatment may include removing the womb, or giving medication or radiation that decrease the ability to become pregnant. </item>
            <item>HPV is a sexually transmitted disease. It is spread through sexual contact with an infected person. This can include penetrative sex (anal or vaginal) or close skin-to-skin genital contact.</item>
            <item>HPV vaccination in younger girls or women, protected sex (condom), and being in relationship with few partners are the best ways to decrease chances of infection. </item>
            <item>As with most sexually transmitted infections, preventative/protective measures can be taken to decrease chances of transmission while still allowing women to engage in sex.</item>
            <item>There is no treatment for HPV infection men, as it is usually cleared by the body itself. HPV is not transmitted with every sexual act and protective measures such as condom use can be pursued. Condom use, however, does not ensure complete protection from transmission. For women treated for HPV, they should delay intercourse to reduce the risk of re-infection.</item>
            <item>Yes. Similar to HIV, the male foreskin acts is where HPV infects or lives. If circumcision is completed, the chance of transmission is lowered, but not completely reduced. Condom use is critical and HPV vaccination (which is recommended between the ages of 9 and 21 for men, and between 9 and 26 for women) is best if possible.</item>
            <item>No.</item>
            <item>omen can be screened for cervical cancer through a pap test, visual inspection with acetic acid (VIA) or HPV test, which will all detect early signs of cervical cancer.  If women have any symptoms of cancer, she can go to a clinic to get an exam to detect cancer.</item>
            <item>HPV can be detected by taking an HPV test, which is then evaluated on a machine in a laboratory.</item>
            <item>The presence of HPV or abnormal cells that could mean precancerous lesions.</item>
            <item>Screening for cervical cancer identifies women how have an increased risk of developing cancer before they actually have cancer.  These women can get simple treatments that reduce or remove their risk of cancer. For the very few women who already have cancer, screening increases the chances of catching cancer in its early stages which is easier to treat. </item>
            <item>While it may be invasive and somewhat uncomfortable for a healthcare provider to inspect the vagina/cervix during an exam, it is important to visualize and collect cells from the area for testing.</item>
            <item>Yes. Early stage cancer is much easier to treat. Screening does not usually detect early cervical cancer, but rather signs that women may be at risk of developing cancer. </item>
            <item>If a woman screens negative for cervical cancer, she should screen again after 5 years. While this may seem like a long time, the speed of cervical cancer development is slow enough to allow this time period. Women with HIV have a higher risk of getting HPV or developing pre-cancer, so they should be screened every year.</item>
            <item>Screening may be painful for some women. However, self-testing may offer a less painful means for testing. It does not require a pelvic exam, and women can successfully complete it on their own.</item>
            <item>No. Self-testing for the presence of HPV is possible.</item>
            <item>Yes. Self-testing for the presence of HPV is possible.</item>
            <item>No. However, it is important to be treated after a positive diagnosis as to limit the risk of cervical cancer.</item>
            <item>Yes. Advanced cervical cancer can be treated with surgery, radiation, or chemotherapy. Pre-cancerous lesions can be treated with LEEP or cryotherapy. </item>
            <item>HPV infections or pre-cancerous lesions can be treated by destroying the infected or abnormal cells with LEEP or cryotherapy.</item>
            <item>Yes. Chemotherapy can be used for treatment of advanced cervical cancer. However, once HPV infection is treated with cryotherapy, medication is not required for further treatment.</item>
            <item>Women should avoid riding a motorbike and doing very heavy work for the first few days after treatment. Women should avoid sex for the first four weeks after treatment. These will all reduce the risk of bleeding and infection.</item>
            <item>A single treatment for HPV works to prevent cervical cancer for almost all women.  For women who already have cancer, the frequency of treatment will be based on stage of cancer and eligibility for different treatment options. Women should talk with their doctor to determine the most appropriate option.</item>
            <item>Yes. Late stage cervical cancer can be difficult to control, especially if it spreads to other areas of a women’s body.</item>
            <item>No. A hysterectomy is the removal of the uterus (womb) and is not necessary for HPV infection. This option for treatment of advanced cervical cancer.</item>
            <item>A single treatment for HPV works to prevent cervical cancer for almost all women.</item>
            <item>The treatments for HPV infection reduce the risk for re-infection, but yes, women can be re-infected with HPV.  This is why it’s important to get regular screening.</item>
            <item>The HPV vaccine provides women with safe, effective, long-lasting protection from cancers caused by HPV. HPV does not work, however, to treat HPV infection.</item>
            <item>Women should get the HPV vaccination before sexual debut. The vaccine is most effective if administered before sexual activity is started. Usually, girls receive the vaccine between ages 11-12, but can get it as early as 9 years old and into their early 20s. Kenya is working to make HPV vaccination available in health facilities.</item>
            <item>The HPV vaccine should be available at local clinics, possibly within schools during selected days, or during outreach/campaign days led by local health officials. Kenya is working to make HPV vaccination available, and we think it should be in clinics within the next year.</item>
            <item>Yes. Boys of similar age (11-12yo) should be vaccinated. While cervical cancer is not a concern for men, other HPV-related cancers such as penile, anal, or oral cancers are possible. </item>
            <item>No. Men are not affected by cervical cancer because they do not have a uterus/cervix. Men are, however, affected by other HPV-related cancers such as penile, anal, and oral cancers. These are much more uncommon than cervical cancer, which is why men are not screened for HPV.</item>
            <item>No. They are not at risk for cervical cancer. The HPV-related diseases that men have are so uncommon that screening is not necessary.</item>
            <item>No. While HPV infection is very common for both men and women, they are not born with the infection. HPV infection is acquired through sex with an infected individual.</item>
            <item>No. While men are usually carriers of the infection until it is cleared by their body, not all men have HPV at all times.</item>
            <item>Yes. Both men and women can be affected by HPV. HPV-related cancers are possible for both sexes. These are much more uncommon than cervical cancer, which is why men are not screened for HPV.</item>
            <item>No. Currently, there is no recommended HPV screening protocol for men. HPV-related cancers are much more uncommon than cervical cancer in men, which is why men are not screened for HPV.</item>
            <item>No. While there is a treatment for women, there is not currently an approved treatment for men. Instead, the infection is usually cleared on its own. </item>
            <item>No. While they are both sexually transmitted infections, they are very different viruses.  Most women who get HPV will clear it on their own.</item>
            <item>Yes. Women with HIV have an increased risk for HPV and cervical cancer because their bodies do not clear the virus as quickly as women without HIV. Being on HIV medications may help HIV-positive women lower their risk of HPV and cervical cancer, but women with HIV should be screened more frequently, every year.</item>
            <item>Yes. Because they are distinct viruses, a woman can be infected with one and not the other</item>
            <item>Yes. Because they are distinct viruses, a woman can be infected with one and not the other. However, if a woman is HIV positive, it may increase her risk of contracting HPV due to a weakened immune system.</item>
            <item>cervical cancer can be managed with treatment if detected early. The ability to cure cervical cancer is based on stage. If in an earlier stage, surgery can be curative. </item>
            <item>No. There is no cure for the virus. Treatment with cryotherapy gets rids of most of the HPV and destroys the cells that HPV would turn into cancer. Most women only need one treatment for HPV</item>
            <item>No. For most women, the infection is naturally cleared from the body. However, some women may develop cervical cancer.</item>
            <item>Invasive cervical cancer can take between 10-15 years after initial infection with HPV to develop. Earlier stage cancerous or pre-cancerous lesions may develop in a shorter amount of time. </item>
            <item>Lack of HPV vaccination, unprotected sex, multiple partners and other infectious diseases such as HIV can lead to an increase in risk of HPV and cervical cancer.?</item>
            <item>The decision to tell her husband is ultimately up to the woman. In many cases that we have seen, husbands can be very supportive, providing funds and other help to obtain treatment. Often, men have a lot of questions about HPV, and want to understand better how to help their wives get treatment, recover and prevent reinfection. We can help answer husbands’ questions. Some women may not feel comfortable talking to their husbands, if they fear violence or concerns about promiscuity. Sometime alternative social support from friends or family can help women understand and access treatment.</item>
            <item>Women can have bleeding or infection at the site on the cervix where they have been treated if they have sex too soon after treatment. They are also at increased risk for re-infection with HPV while the cervix is healing, so should avoid intercourse during that time</item>
        </string-array>
        <string-array name="answers_group_11" />
    </resources>
